C++ is the tool and the core guidelines is
C++ 是工具 核心准则是
the beginnings of a rule book about how to use it well.
一本关于如何使用的规则手册
It was a project, I started it,
这是个项目我开始了
and I found other people were having the same kind of idea that you can't just
我发现别人也有同样的想法
give people a power tool like that without telling them how to do it, use it.
给人一个不告诉他们怎么做的动力工具 用它
So I joined up with some friends of mine that works at
所以我和我的一些朋友一起工作
Microsoft and some at Facebook now,
微软和 Facebook 上的一些人
and some Googlers have contributed,
一些谷歌公司的人
some people from CERN has contributed.
欧洲核研究组织的一些人也做出了贡献
If you go to GitHub,
如果你去 GitHub
you can find that there are lots and lots of contributors,
你可以发现有很多很多的投稿人
and even more gives us ideas when we talk.
更能让我们在谈话时产生想法
Basically, it's an attempt to say what's good programming.
基本上 这是一个尝试说什么是好的编程
How can we can what a good programmer knows about modern C++.
我们如何能让一个好的程序员了解现代的 C++
So the way it's organized is first, there's introduction,
所以它的组织方式首先是介绍
about 25 pages or so of basically philosophy because you
大概有 25 页左右的基本哲学
can't give specific rules that are
无法给出特定规则
coherent without some notion of what's the overall aims,
不知道什么是整体目标
what's the overall design,
什么是整体设计
what are the rules of the game in general.
一般的游戏规则是什么
So if people want to start to use the core guidelines,
所以如果人们想开始使用核心准则
read the first pages about philosophy and such and take from what it is.
阅读关于哲学的第一页 从它的内容中取去
It's philosophy.
这是哲学
But then comes the real rules,
但真正的规则是
which says this is a way you can use a for loop.
这说明你可以用一个循环
This is a way you can organize your error handling.
这是您可以组织错误处理的方法
This is what you have to be careful when you write concurrent code and
这就是你写并发代码时要小心的东西
there are several hundred rules of that sort,
有 100 条规则
and pick some, and read them and see if they make sense to you.
挑选一些 看看他们 看看他们是否对你有道理
See if they're applicable to your code base and the way you do things.
看看它们是否适合你的代码库和你做事的方式
This is what we do now.
这就是我们现在所做的
But that's not the way it's designed.
但这不是它设计的方式
What we've really, really want is a static analyzer that runs over your code,
我们真正想要的是一个静态分析仪 它运行着你的代码
and then tells you, this piece of code breaks rule number C33.
然后告诉你这个代码打破了规则编号 C33
This thing here look at rule F13.
这里看的是 F13 规则
With a bit of luck, you can click on that message,
运气好一点你可以点击那个信息
and it will drop you into the core guidelines,
它会让你进入核心准则
and all the core guidelines are organized like this here.
所有核心准则都是这样组织起来的
First, there is the number and what it's called,
首先有这个号码和它叫什么
which is a descriptive title,
这是一个描述性的标题
then there's a rationale,
那就有理由
usually one to three lines short,
通常是一至三行
then an example, and then anything else you want to know.
然后再举一个例子 然后你想知道的其他事情
So for the more interesting rules,
所以对于更有趣的规则
there'll be several examples,
会有几个例子
and there will be notes and reminders and things like that.
会有笔记和提示之类的
But the way we want to get to is that you don't actually go and read the rules,
但我们想要的方式是你不去看规则
you fire them up on your tool,
你把它们用在你的工具上
and it'll tell you what to read.
它会告诉你要读什么
A beginning of that can be found now in Microsoft Visual Studio.
现在 可以在 Microsoft Visual Studio中找到开始
Microsoft guys wasn't works on that.
微软的人根本就不这么做
That's probably the best one just now.
那可能是现在最好的了
It ships with every Visual Studio.
它与每个 Visual Studio一起提供
You may have to install it, but it's there,
你可能要安装它但是它在那里
and there's a bit coming in the Klang-Tidy has some of the rules too.
克朗蒂迪也有一些规则
So we're working on it.
我们正在努力